# **Everett Diuguid**

everett.diuguid@gmail.com (919) 801-8756 Raleigh, NC

https://github.com/diuguid https://diuguide.github.io/portfolio\_react/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/everett-diuguid-583632197/

Web developer with an eye for design and a proven ability to communicate, adapt, and learn on the fly. Excels in fast paced, collaborative team environments that require attention to detail, hard work, and the ability to adapt. Experience working in a remote setting with group projects utilizing GitBash/GitHub version control, Zoom, Trello and GitHub kanban boards, and Slack. Excited to join a team with a focus on mobile-first design and building better web-experiences.

#### **Technical Skills**

- HTML5
- CSS
- Javascript/ES6
- MongoDB

- ReactJS
- iQuery
- Bootstrap
- NodeJS

- **Express**
- Express-HandleBar
- Git/GitHub
- MySQL

#### Education

# University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill | Chapel Hill, NC

☐ Full-Stack Web Development Certificate, completed November 2020

#### Appalachian State University | Boone, NC

- Bachelors of Arts, History
- Bachelors of Arts, Spanish

medical professionals.

#### F

Pr	ojects	
Ya	Yard-Pal   Repo: https://github.com/diuguide/yard-pal, Link: https://yard-pal.herokuapp.com/	
	MERN-Stack retail app utilizing authentication to create individualized "yard sales" online.	
	Developed and implemented front-end design	
	Coordinated with back end team on testing routes	
	facilitating integration into front end design	
	HTML/CSS/Java, Bootstrap 4, Express, ReactJS, MongoDB, NodeJS	
ls	It Open?   Repo: https://github.com/diuguide/is_it_open, Link: https://diuguide.github.io/is_it_open/	
	A web-api search application where users can search for local business info with matching covid-19 data.	
	Designed front-end layout, structured backend code to support search functionality	
	HTML/CSS/Java, jQuery, Ajax/API	
My	<pre>/riad   Repo: https://github.com/diuguide/symptom_tracker, Link: https://symptomtracker2.herokuapp.com/</pre>	
	A patient symptom tracking app. Create, update, and export personal symptom records for review by	

**Weather Map** | Repo: https://github.com/diuguide/weather\_map, Link: https://diuguide.github.io/weather\_map/

- ☐ Weather search application utilizing a web-api to provide users with current and forecasted weather data for any location.
- ☐ Designed front-end layout and back-end code to support search function.

☐ Collaborated with team members on front-end and back-end design.

☐ HTML/CSS/Java, Bootstrap 4, Express, Express-Handlebars, MySQL, NodeJS

## **Work History**

### Local 22 Bar and Grill, Durham, NC | September 2018 - March 2020:

- Server on a 10 person team
- Marketed and distributed products sourced from local farmers

## Buku: Global Street Food - Raleigh, NC | June 2018 - September 2018:

- Server on a 40 person team
- Crafted unique customer experiences utilizing a diverse global food and drink menu

# Crispy Gyoza Japanese Dumpling Food Truck, Raleigh, NC | May 2018 - June 2018:

- Member of a 2 person team
- Adapted daily to customer volume and truck location by adjusting menu prices and selection to maximize
  profits and ensure smooth functionality while maintaining customer satisfaction

#### Bistro Roca & Antler's Bar, Blowing Rock, NC | May 2016 - April 2018:

- Server on a 15 person team
- Ensured customer satisfaction utilizing high quality products and attention to detail while anticipating and properly addressing customer needs

#### **Humble Pie Tapas, Raleigh NC | May 2012 - August 2015:**

- Server on a 10 person team
- Demonstrated skill in booking, organizing, and executing small and large scale events

#### Moonlight Pizza Company - Raleigh, NC | May 2013 - August 2013:

- Line cook on 2 person team
- Hand-crafted high quality products quickly while adhering to menu criteria and food safety guidelines
- Communicated effectively in a bi-lingual work environment

## Sawmill Taproom - Raleigh, NC | September 2011 - June 2012:

- Line cook on a 10 person team
- Learned to work effectively on a team in close quarters while maintaining efficiency and adherence to health guidelines
- Communicated effectively in a bi-lingual work environment

#### The Busy Bee Café/The Hive - Raleigh, NC | April 2010 - June 2011:

- Bar Support on a 20 person team
- Provided support maintaining inventory, cleanliness and efficiency distributing products over the bar